Yes...
I've always felt as though there is someone beyond the window.
But, there's not the slightest chance of anyone being there.
I wake up, and I regret.
I regret looking for that someone.
Just like always.
Dear Tomoya.
It's your week's allowance and lunch money.
Ah, right. It's time you go to school, isn't it?
I just got back... from work.
Did you pick up the money I left you?
There is nowhere...
...where I belong.
But for no real reason... I did go to school.
One of those force of habit things.
Suki tooru yume o mite ita Yawarakai eien
I was having a transparent dream
It was a tender eternity
It's really beautiful.
My heart is dancing.
Kaze no yona kasuko na koe ga
The faint, wind-like voice
It's only now.
In less then a week,
Takai sora kara boku ho yonde iru
Is calling me from the high sky
If I take off while like this
they'll all fall to the ground.
Yes, but...
Kono mama tobi tateba doko ni datte yukeru
I can go anywhere
...they'll bloom again next year.
They will bloom beautifully the year after that, and the year after that, too.
Kasaneta teto te no nakani
If we can see a little future
Chiisana mirai ga mietara
Within our joined hands
Hikari no naka yurameita kotobamo omoi mo zenbu
Then the words, thoughts, everything
That swayed in the light-
We're late.
The bell rang a long time ago.
See ya.
Harukana kimi made nokosazu tsutaete kitto
Surely, I'll unreservedly tell them
To the distant you
Um, if you don't mind...
...will you walk up this hill together?
Walk up the hill together?
Why?
I can make it this far every day.
But no matter what, I can't walk up the rest of the hill.
It's strange, isn't it? But I can't help it.
Then... Then can I follow you?
I'll just follow your back up the hill.
Is that fine?
I didn't answer her.
It doesn't matter who walks behind me.
I just walk wherever I want.
But...
But... Now that I think back...
That was when I first met her.
It was when everything began.
I'm Furukawa Nagisa.
What's your name?
Why does it matter? You just followed me.
I would want to know your name in case I see you next time and want to say hi.
We won't see each other.
Even if we do, just act like you don't know me.
I'm Furukawa Nagisa.
I heard that already.
Yes.
I'm Okazaki Tomoya.
Okazaki Tomoya-san...
Thank you very much.
I was able to walk up the hill
and make it all the way to school.
Hey, Okazaki, if you're that bored,
wake up Sunohara sitting next to you.
Just so you know, he's not the best at waking up.
I told you to wake him up, so wake him up!
Hey, Sunohara, wake up.
Sunohara!
Don't bite my ear!
Stop... Stop licking...
Okazaki, what are you going to have for lunch?
Bread.
Bread, eh?
Yeah, the cafeteria's stuffed bread is pretty good.
But it's really crowded.
Fried noodle bread!
Ham cutlet bread!
Ginger roast bread!
So all the stuffed bread will be sold out.
I'll pay for you, so go buy some.
Seriously?
In that case...
I'll get myself moving!
You wanna die or what?
We're all in line, you see?
Damn it...
Never give up!
Sunohara Youhei, swimming all the way to the goal.
The gold medal he always dreamed of.
The prize is stuffed bread.
Go for it, Sunohara!
Sunohara, you can do it!
I told you not to cut.
Okazaki-san.
Okazaki Tomoya-san.
This is a nice place, don't you think?
The wind is nice, too, and it's quiet.
Yeah, since it's off limits.
When the lifestyle guidance staff finds you, you'll get yelled at.
I'll say I'm sorry when that happens.
Do you come here often?
Um...
Only from time to time?
Today's the first time.
It was my first time at school in a while, so I was wondering what I should do during the lunch break.
Usually you spend it eating lunch.
Unless, you've already eaten.
Sweet bean bread.
I'm about to buy sweet bean bread and eat.
The sweet bean bread at the cafeteria is really good.
It's crowded down there now because of the stuffed breads,
but the sweet bean bread usually has leftovers, even though they're really good.
So I go, buy them, and eat them.
Okazaki!
I made you wait...
Sorry...
I apologize...
The food stand was crowded like crazy.
Even with my best efforts,
I could only buy sweet bean bread.
And that pissed me off, so I used the entire ¥1000.
You know I don't eat sweet bean bread.
But given the situation, please, eat it.
It's yours.
Sweet bean bread.
You haven't had lunch yet, right?
Bye.
Hey, Okazaki!
I said wait! Tomoya!
Right. The Founders Festival's coming up.
All the clubs are working hard with preparations.
Compared to that, we aren't in any clubs, so we have it easy.
So Okazaki, who was that girl on the roof?
I don't know.
You're going to play dumb?
She's Furukawa Nagisa.
I don't know anything more than that.
That's enough to say you know her.
But I don't recall seeing her on campus before.
It's intolerable how students are oblivious to the problems this school is facing.
The student council must be clear on these problems and state them to the school!
That is the reason why I am announcing my bid for student council president!
Sakagami Tomoyo! Sakagami Tomoyo!
I strongly believe that Tomoyo is the most suited to being the student body representative.
Vote for Sakagami Tomoyo!
A double event with the Founders Festival
and student council presidential election, eh?
It'll be hectic for a while.
Pay back my ¥1000.
Eh?
You wasted it, so pay me back in full.
Let me think about that.
You'd better  think about it.
But really, she was a cute girl.
Just think of the ¥1000 as an investment in her.
Like I will.
I'm having the dream again.
The dream of wandering about, searching for someone.
Then, I finally realize.
I'm just the mind and don't have a body.
That's why that someone didn't notice me, either.
So first, I started to look for my body.
I looked for it in a hurry and in panic.
And I finally found a container for myself.
Even then, I didn't think I'd meet the person anytime soon.
There was no sign the person, either.
Beyond my eyes were endless plains that stretched to the horizon.
Tomoya. Tomoya.
I was able to come home a little earlier than usual.
Should I toast some bread for you?
You should eat something before you go to school.
Tomoya-kun.
I don't need any.
Tomoya.
My mother died when I was five.
I've been raised by my father ever since.
I'm sure it was hard for him to work
and take care of me at the same time.
I understand that well.
But...
But I started having that dream that freezes
my heart before I started elementary school,
and unknowingly, I started not to speak with my father.
On top of that, the fatal accident took place.
It was autumn of my 3rd year of junior high, when admission to a high school through a sports scholarship looked promising.
Tomoya!
I'm home, Tomoya!
Dad's back with a gift!
Come on, eat up. It's the supreme sushi set.
I don't want it.
What?
And you smell sick of alcohol.
Here, just eat.
I said I don't need it!
Tomoya!
Tomoya? Tomoya-kun?
The shoulder tendon is ripped.
The doctor diagnosed it as such...
...and my basketball life ended.
What?
Like I said...
Huh?
Like I said, I wanted to ask for a favor from you again.
"Favor" you say...
Please let me walk up the hill behind you.
We're late again.
It's all right.
If all you need is a back to follow up,
there are plenty of others.
Just ask other people.
Don't tell me you waited for me.
Yes, I was.
You've got to be kidding me.
Okazaki Tomoya-san. I got to know the name.
It's a very ill-intentioned ambush.
Yes, I was ambushing.
The hill's nothing.
Why can't you walk this up alone?
There's nothing...
Nothing?
Even if I went to school, I don't know what I should do.
There is nothing fun...
nor is there a reason I have to be there.
I can't go to a place where I know there's nothing.
I get worried, my legs stop moving, and I shake.
You said you liked the sweet bean bread there.
Yes, it's good.
Then walk up the hill to eat the sweet bean bread.
Yes, I guess... But sweet bean bread isn't enough...
Then find something.
Find something you need to do at school.
Something?
Find that, and then no more ambushing.
See ya.
Furukawa Nagisa.
She's a senior like us, but she's probably a year or two older than us.
She was sick all last year,
so she's repeating her senior year.
No wonder we've never seen her around before.
If you have anything else you want to know, say so.
My information network comes in handy.
What?
¥500.
No IOUs.
I never asked.
Oh, no. Your face says you want to know more.
No, it doesn't.
Sunohara Youhei.
Former star midfielder of the soccer team.
Right now, he got booted from the club and is just a punk.
He got in as a sports recruit,
but he snapped in the middle of a game.
I didn't hear what the exact reason was,
but he broke another player's teeth,
bit off an ear,
and he kicked his coach's most important appendage with full power.
He's usually a carefree guy, but he got labeled a monster when he snaps, and now I'm the only one he talks to at school.
No stars out tonight.
By the way, unlike me, he's got guts.
I mean, even after he got booted from the team, he's still living in the dorm.
In the dorm where only sports recruited students can live.
Well, what can I do?! My family's poor,
so I can't find a new apartment now and pay rent!
He brags how he's managed through
the school's multiple attempts to get him out.
I want some ramen.
You bought a big size one, didn't you?
No! This is my breakfast!
You can't have it!
Windy weather lasted for a few days after a rain...
...and that ended the sakura for the year.
Um...
Hey. Haven't seen you in a while.
Yes. It's been a while.
I had a little fever and was absent from school.
I see.
Yes.
But look. I'm better now and am walking up the hill myself.
It's natural to walk up alone.
Yes.
Tomoya-san, I found something at school that I look forward to.
I've thought about it, and I found it.
That's good.
Yes.
Thank you very much.
It's all due to your advice.
I didn't do anything.
What?
Oh, nothing.
Hello.
I did it!
Hey, I did it!
I was able to buy stuffed bread today!
Look, dumpling sandwich and fried noodle bread.
Hello.
What is this?
What are you doing?
Furukawa, if stuffed bread is all right, come stuff yourself.
Just kidding.
Tatata, tada!
What is this?
Recruiting members?
The Theater Club?!
Yes. I'm recruiting members.
I will reestablish the Theater Club that closed down last year because all the members left.
I'm making a poster for that.
Theater Club, eh?
This... This drawing looks like a marshmallow, if not an egg.
What is it?
It's the Big Dango Family.
It's the Big Dango Family that was popular when I was a child.
I drew them since I love them.
Dango, dango, dango, dango.
Dango family is a big family.
Always a happy big family.
The house is always like a sports day.
Ready go, run run run. Family marathon.
Time for a bath. Get inside. Breath-holding competition.
Dango. Dango's a big family.
Oh yeah, I remember that song back when I was a kid.
The boom still lives within me.
The big family where everyone cares about each other.
I love them so much.
So, this Theater Club is what you mentioned earlier...
Yes. It's the fun I found at school.
I will reestablish the Theater Club.
I will perform a play at the Founders Festival.
I think I'll be able to walk up
the hill every day if I have this goal.
Anyway, I'll make lots of posters
and post them everywhere around the school.
Dango, dango, dango, dango.
Dango family is a big family.
Always a happy big family.
She was singing so cheerfully.
What was that bright light I saw eight years ago on the rooftop about?
Saito Electrical Construction, Ltd.
Hey, Okazaki.
Get in.
You'll catch a cold.
Come back to work already.
It might help you getting over things if you work up a sweat.
I'm sorry, Yoshino-senpai.
Don't worry. You're not being treated as absent without permission.
I'm telling the president that you call in every day.
I'm sorry.
I'll need some more time.
I see. Okay.
I'm sorry.
Everyone's worried about you.
They're all thinking that you're depressed again.
They're all waiting to hear from you.
Everyone's thinking about you.
I'm sorry.
Nagisa-chan often said,
"Big families always think about each other."
I'm sorry!
Okazaki!
What? What's wrong?
Come with me!
What? To where?
Just come!
That! Take a look.
Void?
What do you mean void?
Void means void. It means invalid.
Member recruitment for clubs was only allowed until last week.
Therefore member recruiting outside of the timeframe is against the rules.
Sakagami.
This forceful act had to have been done by the current student council's executives.
They're eggheads.
Sakagami!
Wh-Where are these executives?!
I don't know.
This poster is handmade, you know?!
It's a message from the heart,
drawn with heart and passion!
Damn this cross!
Guys are strolling around campus looking for these posters.
So they can put the cross on or rip them off walls.
Okazaki! Let's go!
Sunohara!
Don't snap!
If you do, you'll get expelled this time!
Let's go check this out!
Yeah.
He's seriously snapped.
This is interesting.
Come on, let's go.
They got this one, too.
Crap, even here.
Damn it!
Furukawa.
Okazaki! This way!
Meet me on the roof after school!
Yes.
Wait for me on the roof!
Yes...
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
Stop right there!
It's started!
They're over at the old school building.
I heard blood is all over the place already.
Where are they?
This way! Hurry!
What are you doing?
What are you  guys doing to a poster someone drew?!
We were only committing fair warning on illegal posters!
Warning? Fair?!
Don't give me that shit!
You guys are the illegal ones!
How are we illegal?
Like this!
And this!
And this, too!
Take that.
What are you all doing?
The lunch break is already over.
Go back to your classes already.
Keep your hands off of me!
Everyone, leave.
Don't be late for your classes.
Yes.
I don't know what the cause was,
but you have to talk first, Sunohara-kun.
Yes.
Return to your class now.
Yes...
That was a surprise.
I heard there was teacher who practices aikido and teaches second year classes.
It has to be her. What a surprise.
If I'm right, her name was...
Ibuki!
Ibuki Kouko!
Cool girls like her are right in my strike zone.
You perv.
How many did you draw in total?
Fourteen.
I see. Some of them either got
thrown away or taken away by them.
I collected all the ones that I could find.
What a horrible thing they did.
I'm all right.
"All right"?
Furukawa...
I'm all right. I'll draw them again.
I'll draw them again and post them everywhere on campus.
You can't. They'll get you again!
They put the cross and the void sign again.
But I already made up my mind that I'll reestablish the Theater Club.
I never knew there was a deadline on the recruiting period.
Three! If there are three members, it gets acknowledged as a club.
Furukawa...
I'll draw the posters!
I'm sure there are people who want to join the Theater Club.
There have to be!
Furukawa, why do you want to do theater so much?
Why?
I can't tell you the reason now.
But...
But I want to do it.
Okay, then go draw the poster.
A really amazing one, but just one will do.
We'll photocopy it.
We'll make a hundred or two hundred copies of it.
Then Sunohara and I will post them all around the school.
Photocopy...
That's it, Okazaki! That's the way to go!
All right, leave it to us. If they're just copies, no matter how many crosses they make,
we'll just post up more from over them!
This is a war!
I'll take this to the extreme against the student council executives!
War, eh? That's not very peaceful.
Sensei, here she is.
It's her.
This Furukawa-san is you, right?
Ibuki-sensei.
Furukawa, you know her?
She was the advisor of the
Theater Club before it closed down.
I-I see.
Furukawa-san, you're interested in theater?
Yes. I filled out the member form once before.
Oh, you did?
But I couldn't come to school soon after
and had to be absent from school for the entire year,
and the club was closed down while I was gone.
I see.
Yes.
Then, if the club is reestablished...
I'd be very happy.
It is past the deadline, but if you can get members together, I'll talk to the school.
You mean that?
So keep at it.
Yes!
The plan ended in failure.
No one wanted to join.
The reestablishment of the
Theater Club was going to end in vain...
...or was supposed to have.
There's nothing we can do, Furukawa.
This world favors comedy.
Serious stuff don't get much attention.
We did what we can, so we have to face the results, right?
Right, Okazaki?
Huh? Yeah.
The poster was good, you know.
Nagisa kept working.
She used an amazing secret trick.
She worked really hard.
Wh-Wha?
H-Hold on a minute, Furukawa.
I'll have you two fill out the member form.
Then that makes three including me.
Furukawa!
Then everything will be solved.
The Theater Club will have Ibuki-sensei as the advisor and will restart.
Sorry Furukawa. I can't do that.
I'm not going to participate in a club.
Yeah. We're staying away from clubs!
Both Okazaki and I are able to be who we are because we aren't in any clubs!
Besides, I'm not into acting.
Like water and oil!
He's a basketball man,
and I was once called the soccer prodigy.
Yes, I know, it's about the past.
In other words, screaming "You idiot" at the sunset,
or saying "I love you. J-J-Ju-Ju..."
for a love scene are total mismatches for us!
We don't comprehend that kind of language!
Are you fine with this argument?
Huh? Yeah.
Do you understand?!
Stop giggling.
Please don’t worry too much.
It'll be fine.
Fine? What about?
I plan on doing a solo play on the Founders Festival's stage.
Solo play?
I won't ask either of you to stand on the stage or recite lines.
I promise-
Found it!
Excuse me.
Um... Um... That's Dangos on a Stick from the Big Dango Family series, right?
Yes. You know your stuff.
You're exactly right.
I've been searching for it. I'll have it.
Oh, but I don't have money on me, so may I come get it tomorrow after school?
Sure, that's fine.
That's great. I'm so happy.
Please don't sell it until then.
Don't worry. The boom was long ago.
Nobody wants it now.
You can take it with you today. Come pay me tomorrow.
Really?
Thank you very much!
Dango, dango, dango, dango.
Dango family is a big family.
Always a happy big family.
That was the extent of our resistance.
We were signed up to the club, going with the flow.
With the flow...
I guess that was very much alike me.
And, like always, after I get carried with the flow,
I'll regret it later.
A solo play.
That sounds good.
It's very suitable for this small Theater Club that has just started.
"Small", eh? She's right.
So small.
What will the scenario be?
Yes, I'll work on it.
What play are you going to perform?
On what play will you base it on?
There are many to choose from, like Shakespeare or Baudelaire's poems.
No, um... It'll be an original work.
Original?
Your own?
Yes.
I see. I can't wait to see it.
We're less than a month before the
Founders Festival, so you have much to work on.
Yes.
I'll help you out anytime you need assistance.
Okay then, stage crew boys.
This room will be the club room starting today,
so sort out the necessary and unnecessary things.
Where's your answer?
Yes!
That concludes the first new Theater Club's meeting.
Good luck everyone.
She said we're the stage crew.
Looks like we are now.
I had a brighter image of a Theater Club, but I guess shadows exist everywhere.
Can't agree more.
I'll help out as well.
Your house?!
Yes.
Your house, eh...
Yes, my house.
Why your house?
I'm saying, please join me for dinner.
Then we'll have a meeting.
Dinner?
Meeting?
I need to write the script, and I'm sure you two need to work out your schedules with this new commitment.
Who cares about working out schedules?
Do it yourself.
I don't know anything about scenario and stuff, and I'm not interested in it.
But dinner...
I can't go to other people's house just to go eat dinner!
Convenience store food matches my stomach best.
Right, Sunohara?
Hey, Sunohara!
Sorry, I have something to take care of today!
Bye!
Stop, you!
You plan on leaving me at a time like this?
No, I seriously have business to take care of.
Stop screwing around with me.
I have a part-time job.
Part-time job?
I heard my house's doing horrible financially.
My monthly allowance hasn't been sent to me in a while.
I know what it's like right now,
but I've decided to pick up a job. Three times a week.
A senpai... A senpai from our school hooked me up.
I see.
Today's the first day. I don't want to be late.
Bye.
Sunohara.
Sorry I stopped you.
Do your best.
Your house is a bakery?
Furukawa Bread is famous around here.
I'm home.
Welcome home, Nagisa.
Welcome.
Oh? I had heard you were bringing two guests.
There's only one.
I get it! He must be Okazaki Tomoya-san.
You guessed right, Mom.
Of course I can tell; he's exactly as you described.
How did she describe me?
Shh. You can't, Mom. We promised you wouldn't tell.
Therefore, I can't tell you.
Where's Dad?
Over at the park.
Playing baseball with the children
from the neighborhood like always.
Ah, baseball.
Yes, baseball.
You must be Okazaki Tomoya.
You've been sucking up to Nagisa and finally made your way into our house.
No, um... I never...
If you're a man, then fight me!
Come to the park!
Dad...
Don't worry.
Dinner will be ready soon.
I know.
What are you doing, Okazaki?!
Catch it with everything you've got!
Life is...
...about fights!
The moment you let down your guard...
...you get stamped as a loser!
Hey!
I've never played baseball before.
I'm not interested in it, either.
Just throw the ball back already.
If I catch the ball you throw,
I can judge how big a man you are.
"How big"?
Big as in how?
A, B+, or C-.
I'm judging if you're suitable for Nagisa or not.
I don't want you making judgments on me!
Don't get out of the way this time!
Good! Now throw it back!
Why don't you throw it back properly?!
The tendon in my shoulder's torn,
so my right arm can only go up this high.
Akio-san! Dinner's ready!
Coming.
Akio-san, has the shirataki absorbed enough flavor?
Yes, it's the best. Sanae-chan's the best cook.
You are the iron chef.
A hottie on top of that, too.
Akio-san, you have rice on your face.
Take it off for me.
Hey, it's almost strange how well your parents get along.
They're off now.
Thank you.
They're always like this.
Always?
Here, Sanae-chan. Say "Ah".
Ah~
It's not "almost". They are strange.
Tomoya-san. Say "Ah".
You've got to be kidding me.
How about some, Okazaki?
Yes, thank you.
You're still in high school, remember that.
Akio-san, you're so mean.
But, Sanae-chan loves Akio-san.
Yes, I do.
I can't take this.
Hey, grumpy face.
Want one?
Don't mind me if I do.
He fell for it again.
Oh, Akio-san.
Aw, that felt good.
Hey, you two go take a shower.
Of course I was joking!
Scenario?
Yes, scenario.
But I don't hear a thing coming from Nagisa's room.
Of course, since she's working on the scenario.
What kind of plot is this original story going to have?
I'm sorry, what was that, Tomoya-san?
Nothing. Go ahead and keep working. Don't mind me.
Okay. Then I'll continue.
You own a lot of the Big Dango Family, eh?
Actually, there is more than this out there.
I will collect them all one day.
All right.
I'll should get myself out of here.
This is one of Akio-san's old pajamas.
Go ahead and use it.
Oh no. I'm leaving now.
Oh, you weren't planning on staying over?
I never intended to.
Just stay.
No...
As a fellow Theater Club member, you plan on leaving Nagisa, who might end up pulling an all-nighter, alone?
N-No...
Then stay.
Okay.
Don't worry; you'll be sharing a bed with me.
Eh?
You got problem with that?
Yes.
Want me to lock you in a figure-four?
You can't sleep?
No. You can't either?
My reason is obvious.
I'm basically sleeping with a wild animal in the same cage.
Dad's snoring must be keeping you up.
Yeah, exactly.
I heard Mom got used to it soon enough.
If you listen to it closely, she says it's cute.
What does it take to hear that?
You smiled. Tomoya-san smiled.
No, I didn't.
Tomoya-san, who always has a grumpy face, smiled.
Be quiet.
You have a very kind face when you smile.
I'm sorry.
I know what I should write.
But I can't write it well, so I can't go to sleep.
Also, I'm happy to have you close to me.
I'm so happy, so it feels like a waste to go to bed.
I'm sorry.
Dream... It's about a dream.
It's about the dream that I've been having since I was little and am still having.
That's what I want to write about.
What kind of dream is it?
I'll share it with you once the scenario is done.
Okay.
You know, I also have a dream that I've been having since I was little.
How does it go?
Mine's a nightmare.
I always wake up in a cold sweat.
I don't even want to talk about it.
Furukawa.
Thank you.
Today was the first time in a while I ate a meal with so many people.
It was really fun.
I was very warm, and it made me happy.
I'm glad. I'm happy, too.
Soon after that day, I saw the dream starting from where I'd left off last time.
But this time, the dream didn't end with the repetition of hopeless situations.
It had a turn where I could almost catch a glimmer of hope.
Words echoed in my head.
"The Tree of Promise."
"At the end of this wilderness, there is the Tree of Promise."
"It awaits you."
Tree of Promise?
Waiting for me?
What is?
Who is?
It was clear to me what was waiting.
It must the "someone" that I'd been searching for.
Something burned inside of me.
Something sparked inside my heart.
I ran with everything I had.
Aiming for the end of the wilderness...
Aiming for the end of the life...
Hey, Okazaki.
Up here.
Sunohara.
He's my senpai, Yoshino. Yoshino Yusuke-san.
This is Okazaki. Former basketball player.
Currently a Theater Club member.
Quit it.
We're short on people. Do you want a part-time job, too?
Y-Yeah...
Give it some thought, Okazaki.
The pay is pretty good.
We're going to the next site.
Coming.
What time are you getting out, Sunohara?
Yoshino-san used to be a famous musician in Tokyo.
Musician?
He was in a rock band and released a lot of CDs.
But for some reason, he dropped out.
Right now, he's come back to this city and is working like any other person.
Doesn't that sound like how we
gave up on soccer and basketball?
No, it's completely different.
He went all the way to standing under the spotlight once.
You're right.
Nagisa. Okazaki What's-His-Name won't be coming tonight?
Pardon me.
I'm sorry.
I can't make it to the Founders Festival's preparations at all.
I'm in charge of Sound and you're Lighting.
I see.
Ibuki-sensei made the decision today.
But Furukawa's scenario is behind schedule.
She might have to wing it on stage that day.
Furukawa has it rough, but we might need to be ready for this thing, too.
Go and see what happens.
That's more fitting for us.
Less things to worry about, right?
Are you serious about this?
The day of the Founders Festival came.
What? You can't do that to us.
Why are you teaching math in English class?
Ah god. This is what I always get from silly students.
Listen. Mathank you very much.
Thank you for you time.
You're joking, right, Furukawa?
I'm sorry, can you repeat that?
Furukawa-san?
I'm sorry...
I couldn't get the scenario done in time.
This is so like us.
The first New Theater Club's performance gets canceled.
Um...
I couldn't get the scenario done in time,
but I plan on standing on the stage.
Furukawa-san?
It's complete inside me.
B-But, Furukawa. We need to read the scenario at least once.
Like for Lighting and Sound.
Or else we won't have a clue what to do.
No, it's fine.
I'll give orders as I watch the stage.
Sensei...
Let's all trust the scenario Furukawa-san has in her heart.
I'm sure it's a very wonderful story.
Akio-san, over here.
Let's see. Where is the auditorium Nagisa will be performing at?
Looks like Nagisa won't be on stage until much later.
Let's have lunch in the meantime.
Yeah. That sounds good.
I knew it.
I knew I'd find you here.
Have you had lunch?
You won't be up until around evening.
You won't last unless you eat something.
We heard there's a cheap but good udon stand,
and Sunohara went dashing to it.
I'm sorry. I don't think my stomach will accept it.
Not much you can do about it, then.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry for causing trouble for everyone.
Stop apologizing!
But...
You will stand on the stage and do as you like.
We'll follow you.
That's what we decided on doing.
Have confidence and do it with pride.
Like Ibuki-sensei said, there's nothing more we can do than trust you.
Yes!
Yeah! That's what I want to hear.
All right.
Good.
I'll see you later.
Make sure you read over the scenario in your heart.
What's wrong?
I think I'm suddenly hungry.
What?
You're so unmanageable.
Fine, wait here.
I'll get you something.
Let me share the reason why I want to do theater so much.
My dad and mom used to work together as actors in a theatrical group.
But after getting married and having me, they gave up on staying actors.
I was physically weak when I was a child, so they chose to be with me all the time.
That's why they quit the theater group,
moved to this city, and started a bakery.
They figured a homemade bakery would let the family always be together.
So... So standing on the stage is a way of thanking my parents.
Showing how well I am...
That I still remember what their dreams were.
Something like that happens in this world, eh?
To pick family over your own dreams...
So you can find something like this if you look for it.
It sounds like a story totally unrelated to me.
What the hell are you saying?
When you get that attitude,
you're supposed to slap them around.
Like this?
Where's my glasses?
Did you bring a costume?
Yes. I borrowed it from my mother.
Let's go. It's almost time.
Yes.
Yo.
Ah, Yoshino-senpai.
I didn't know you were coming to the Founders Festival.
When you're done, I'll be waiting at the usual place.
Okay.
Well, good luck.
Yup. Thank you.
Sensei, you were dating Yoshino-senpai?
I never knew that.
You just dropped something.
Where? Where?
Where?!
Next is a solo play by the Theater Club.
The Empty World.
Lighting, stand by.
First, flow Furukawa-san with the spotlight.
Gotcha.
Sound, ready?
Counting down, ten seconds...
Five seconds...
Slowly come in.
Two...
One...
Go!
Sanae... That's...
Yes. It's the dress I wore at our wedding.
I gave it to Nagisa.
Gave it to her?
Yes. Since I won't have the chance to wear it again.
Well, that's true.
The empty world...
What's there is wind...
...a small ray of light...
...occasional snow...
...and me, who is so tired that there isn't even a tear to shed.
Drop down the music a little.
Sound of wind in the back. Louder slowly.
How much time has passed?
One month?
Two months?
Five years may have passed for all I know.
These days, I can't even recall what I was waiting for.
Change lighting to blue.
Give it a soft feel to it.
Yes, that's good.
But the wind that comes from the ocean...
The familiar, warm wind.
Like the warmth of a mother's hand or a father's kindness.
When that wind covers my body, I will regain my memory.
I will become a little better and come alive once more.
Overlap the sounds of wind and waves.
Increase the volume of BGM a little over time.
Roger.
What I'm waiting for is...
It's your voice.
It's a very small, hesitant voice,
but it's your beautiful voice
that represents your kind heart.
Your voice soaks into my heart.
Your voice and you...
...are what I'm waiting for.
Start Music 2.
Slowly fade Music 1 out.
Sunohara-kun, chase Furukawa-san.
I run.
I run for the end to the empty world.
I heard a voice inside my heart.
"Go to the end of the empty world."
"Someone awaits you there."
"For many, many years, that someone has been waiting for you."
"Just as you were waiting."
And in the end, this is what the voice said.
Okazaki-kun. Continue the music.
Okazaki-kun!
"When you reach the end of the world, you shall witness..."
"...the figure filled with life and shimmering gloriously!"
"That is the Tree of Promise."
This can't be!
Okazaki-kun.
"Someone is waiting for you under that tree!"
Your solo play continued.
There were many things in the way,
but you made it to the Tree of Promise.
But I couldn't get any of the rest of the story into my head.
I was shocked by the fact that for the longest time, you and I had been having the same dream, and I panicked.
I panicked because I always thought I was the only one who dreamed of anything as lonely as this empty world.
Furukawa... I never knew you shared the dream.
You always smiled so kindly
and always acted so cheerfully.
You would just laugh when you were in trouble, and yet you were...
So dear to me.
you are so dear to me.
That's what I felt from the bottom of my heart.
Tomoya-san.
Nagisa!
I love you!
After that, two springs went by.
It's because soon after the Founders Festival,
Nagisa's health went downhill and she had to be away from school for nearly a year.
In other words, Nagisa graduated from high school a year after us.
Nagisa, congratulations on your graduation!
After her graduation, when the sakura were in full bloom, we started living together...
...in this apartment.
Nagisa!
Good evening.
You're back late.
Sakagami.
I stopped by Furukawa Bread today,
and they asked me to bring this to you.
Sanae-san said she wanted you to eat these.
You aren't eating properly, are you?
I thought bread alone wouldn't be enough, so I'm thinking of making some soup.
Let me borrow your kitchen.
I heard you don't go to Furukawa Bread too often.
Ushio-chan's become pretty big.
Coming.
Hello.
What? Sunohara?!
Oh, Sakagami. You're here, too?
Wow, you're here from Tokyo?
Today's a weekday.
Do you have a day off?
Big companies have a thing called paid vacation.
Came on a bullet train and got on a local train. A long tiring trip.
Hey, former Theater Club.
Are you doing well?
If you were, I wouldn't have come.
But...
You're so hopeless; still depressed.
I heard you haven't been going to work at all.
Will you join us for dinner, Sunohara?
You haven't eaten yet, have you?
Yeah, I'll dig in. Thanks.
Okazaki, come over here.
Let's all eat together.
Let's go, Okazaki.
Come on.
Hey, wait a minute. Today's the 24th, isn't it?
It's the monthly anniversary of her death, so let me offer some incense.
Me, too.
It was fun.
Our life in the apartment.
It really was for a short time, but it was fun.
Have a good day.
Later.
I got employed full-time at the part-time position Yoshino-senpai first introduced me to after graduating.
Nagisa worked, too.
Four days a week at a nearby family restaurant.
Can I have some water?
Sir, this is your fifth cup.
It's fine, since I love water.
Watch me.
I often went to the shop with Sunohara, who hadn't left for Tokyo yet, and caused a lot of trouble for you.
We were actually visiting to see you.
To see you working hard with a smile.
We wanted to see you shine.
Hello. Welcome to Earnest Host.
Also, that small apartment really became like a house for the Big Dango Family.
Everyone would come visit us.
Akio's here!
Sanae's here!
The two of us make Akio-Sanae.
Sensei, why are you teaching math in English class?
Oh dear... Silly bakers always ask me that.
Listen this is the real,
mathank you very much.
You stole that joke!
Hello, Sunohara's here!
Sakagami Tomoyo's here!
Fujibayashi Kyou's here!
Three of us make the Suno-Saka-Kyou Trio!
Our apartment isn't a comedy house!
Enough of this!
Wow, looks like everyone's having fun here.
What's today's gathering about?
Yoshino-senpai! Ibuki-sensei!
We have the lovey-dovey couple!
I'm asking you what this gathering is about!
Nothing. We're just hanging out.
Is that so?
That's right.
All right then! Everyone, let's go!
Dango, dango, dango, dango.
Dango family is a big family.
Always a happy big family.
The house is always like a sports day.
Ready go, run run run. Family marathon.
I knew it wasn't me.
Everyone gathered around you.
Time for a bath. Get inside. Breath-holding competition.
Your kindness.
Dango. Dango's a big family.
Your cheerfulness.
Something about you that calmed everyone...
recreated the Big Dango Family here.
But... But who thought you'd...
See ya, Okazaki.
I'll go home today.
Do you like pasta? I'll make some next time I come.
She means spaghetti.
Bye.
Good night.
What's gone wrong with Okazaki?
He didn't say a single word to me in the end.
Sunohara.
There's nothing you can do.
We have to let time take care of it.
I'm so pathetic to be unable to do anything.
The baby seems to have
a healthy heart. It's developing well.
The problem lies with the mother.
Mother? So you mean with Nagisa?
She's been in and out of the hospital since she was young.
Her body is weaker than you think.
If she goes through labor and delivers the baby, the chances of her survival are very slim.
Isn't there a way to save both of them?
Please talk to your daughter.
We'll do the best we can based on her answer.
We have to tell Nagisa everything.
You think so, too, right, Tomoya-san?
Yes.
I already named the baby.
Nagisa...
It's Ushio.
Be it a boy or girl, it'll be Ushio.
Isn't it nice?
Nagisa...
I'm Nagisa.
But Ushio exists closer to the center of the ocean.
It's very noble and moves gallantly through the ocean.
I'm sure the baby won't be physically weak like me, and its heart will be much bigger and stronger.
Nagisa...
Right now, I'm thinking nothing else other than delivering this baby.
It'll be fine.
I want to meet this baby badly.
So I'm sure I'll be fine, too.
I have to be.
Nagisa...
Ushio-chan's born.
It's a girl.
How's the mother?
How's Nagisa doing?
The doctor said for the family to come immediately.
Ushio...
Look at Ushio, Tomoya-san.
Yeah.
I'm glad I met Ushio.
I'm really happy...
Yeah.
I'm happy for you, too, Nagisa.
That's right... I met you... under... many sakura...
Nagisa.
And then, we walked up the hill together.
At the top of the hill is Dad holding Ushio.
Mom's smiling...
Nagisa! Nagisa!
...and everyone's there.
Don't go Nagisa!
I'm so happy...
Everyone's waiting for me.
Nagisa! Don't go!
You don't have to walk up any hill!
You don't have to force yourself up!
Nagisa! Don't go!
Stay! Stay with me!
My beloved Tomoya-san...
Thank you.
Nagisa?
Nagisa!!!
Soon after Nagisa died, I noticed something.
I noticed how I haven't had the nightmare I've been having since childhood for the longest time.
I think... after watching Nagisa's performance at the school's auditorium, I stopped having the nightmare.
But instead, ever since Nagisa died,
a new nightmare started.
To be precise, not a dream, but my life without Nagisa.
This everyday life that I face as reality became like the empty world in the nightmare.
If it's a dream, I can wake up from it as morning comes.
But there is no morning to this empty world.
The world where Nagisa doesn't exist will continue endlessly.
What? What time do you think it is?
I'm off to the night shift, but I had to talk to you.
There's nothing to talk about.
Go home.
Let me make some coffee.
So what do you want?
I heard you're leaving Ushio-chan with
her grandparents and you don't go see her at all.
I heard you haven't done much at all these past five years.
Not a good thing.
Yes, you're being just like me!
Just like how I wronged you after your mother died!
When your mother died, everything went black to me.
As a result, I made you feel lonely at the most crucial time in your life.
I couldn't pay attention to you at all,
and all I could do was bemoan my tragic life.
By the time I noticed it, you had already gone far away.
Just stay far way.
Don't come close to me, just like we haven't been.
I beg you. Please forgive me!
Quit it!
What kind of father kneels before his son?!
I didn't want to see you like that, so that's why I... I...
Leave me alone.
Go home.
I've made you angry again.
I'll be going now.
Oh yeah, Tomoya-kun.
What?
Ah, well... The rain will continue for a while, so don't catch a cold.
Mind your own business.
You're right.
Don't give me this crap...
Stop acting like my father...
Don't give me this...
Cut the crap!
Okazaki! Are you home?!
Get up!
The rain's gone already.
What are you doing?
Pack it up, Kouko.
Two shirts,
four boxers,
some socks,
and one change of long pants.
Okay. I'll pick and choose some other stuff.
Wash your face.
Brush your teeth.
Don't waste any time.
Wh-What is this about?
You're going on a trip.
I'll hear your complaints later.
Just do as I say.
Packed and ready!
All right then, off you go.
Hop in.
Trip you said? Where are we going?
Just a little somewhere.
Somewhere?
Shut up. Keep your mouth shut and sit.
That's right.
Hey! Hey!
All right, hop in.
Sunohara?
Sunohara, were you able to book the tickets?
Yes, Sir!
Got everyone's seats reserved.
Great!
What?
Reserved seats? Everyone?
What is this about?
Hey, over here.
Hello.
Come on, hop on in.
Okay.
There's your bento.
Here's yours Sunohara.
Woohoo.
We woke up early and made them together.
This looks amazing.
Good work.
Eat up, Okazaki.
You haven't had breakfast, right?
What is this about?!
I don't understand, but you're all being too weird!
Senpai! What is this about?!
A camp trip.
Camp?
That's right. It's the Big Dango Family camp trip.
We reserved a lodge by a beach for a week.
We're all going to have a camp there.
Big Dango Family...
Camp trip...
I can't go along with this.
She's not with us anymore...
Nagisa's gone!
I'll go home.
I'll get off at the next station.
I won't let you.
We're taking you no matter what.
I was asked to about ten days ago by a certain person.
So I will take you.
By who?
I can't tell you that.
Please. And I'm sorry.
Tomoya can't stand on his own yet.
Please save him with all of your support.
Father...
He booked the lodge and put together today's plan.
Who?!
You'll figure it out one day.
Once you can stand on your own, you will.
Let's see. We're supposed to get picked up at the platform.
Hey, Sunohara. Go check the fifth platform.
Okay.
Sakagami and Fujibayashi, go check the ticket counter.
Okazaki, you go check the second platform.
Second...
Second platform...
Did Okazaki go?
Yeah. He just went on his way.
This is Dango.
I'll give it to you.
Watch out!
Papa.
Yeah. Hello, Ushio.
Hello.
Yeah.
It was only for a moment, but I saw
the dream again from where I'd left off.
Under the Tree of Promise, was you, Nagisa.
You stood there.
With a smile...
With your usual lovely smile.
Tookude tookude yureteru inaho no umi
Far away, far away, the sea of rice plants wavers
Ho wo age ho wo age mezashita omoi deto
Raising the rice, raising the rice, we aimed for the memory
Bokura wa kyou made no
Do we remember the sad things that have happened before today,
Kanashii koto zenbu oboeteruka, wasuretaka
or have we forgotten them?
Kuroi sono hitomi wa
Takusan no mirai utsusu
Your black pupils
Reflect the many futures
Donna ni kagayaku hoshi yori
Standing here with a heart more beautiful
Kirei na kokoro de koko ni tatte
Than how any star shines
Yawaraka na hikari ga
Haruka na sora o koete Kimi o terasu
Surpasses the distant sky
And illuminates you
Dou shite mo todokanai kedo
Koko kara tada negau
I can’t reach you no matter what
But I simply wish from here
Mashiro na sekai no hate de
At the edge of a pure white world
Nagarete iru tooi utagoe
Azayaka ni hibiku
A drifting, faraway singing voice
Echoes vividly
Nemuru yo koga wo niwa
In your face sleeping on its side
Dango dango dango dango dango daikazoku
Dango, dango, dango, dango, dango no kazoku wa daikazoku!